Arturo Abreu

Front-end Developer



Barcelona, Spain

axa.gomez@gmail.com

arturoabreu.com

+34622056260

WORK EXPERIENCE

Airbnb's Customer Representative

CPM International December, 2018 - June, 2020 · Barcelona, Spain.

- Guiding Airbnb users through the website and troubleshooting.
- · Making use of the Zendesk platform to perform customer service tasks.
- Working closely with teammates to improve efficiency and KPI's.
- · Provided guidance for mediation, resolutions and settlements following the company's guidelines.

Boeing 757 & 767 First Officer

SBA Airlines December, 2016 - December, 2017 - Caracas, Venezuela

- · Assist the flight operations in accordance with the company's standard procedures.
- Enhance at any time, the flight experience in terms of safety, comfort and economy.
- · Ensure proper preparation of the flight's variables such as weather, payload and aircraft performance for mid haul flights.

McDonnell Douglas DC9 & MD82 First Officer

Aeropostal April, 2013 - July, 2016 - Caracas, Venezuela

- · Work alongside the flight crew to perform frequent flights with passengers and cargo.
- · Use crew coordination techniques to monitor aircraft systems and ensure aircraft proper behaviour.
- · Assess flight capabilities under single engine operations.

PROJECTS

Breathing Love

Static website for personal branding, hosted on SiteGround.

Covid Update

Slim app to retrieve and display COVID-19 data.

Sobrio.css

Sobrio.css is a small sober-looking CSS toolkit for element styling and responsive layout.

ABOUT ME

"Born in Venezuela, I became an Airline Pilot and, in the meantime, I created web pages as a hobby. I left my homeland two years ago in the pursuit of new challenges and moved to sunny Barcelona. Currently I dedicate all my time teaching myself how to code and everything web related".

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Semantic use of HTML, accessibility and SEO. Design of responsive layouts with Flexbox and Grid, creation of toolkit libraries using CSS preprocessors such as SASS. Users interaction trough DOM manipulation and API's using modern JavaScript.

ReactJS, Git

Creation of user interfaces with ReactJS main features and project management with version control software such as Git.

EDUCATION

Commercial Pilot

INAC 2010 - 2013 - Puerto La Cruz, Venezuela

Bachellor of Science

U.E CMG 2005 - 2010 - Margarita, Venezuela